poke
Is this year just full of bad punners or does Nick just attract them every year?
//i'm guessing every year, we also have a module with him next year
.368 - that number haunts my dreams
//wazdat? like e^-1 or something, maffs
On that board
/////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
anyone glancing at this would be like aww they're holding hands
NO, THIS IS WAR
//i am fairly sure it's fucking obvious we're fighting

//did you see that metric fuckton of tiny pieces of paper on the pavement at the bottom of park street?
No? Are you sure it was a metric fuckton?
//ye
---CHOICE
To model choice we introduce the MonadAlt class

class Monad M => MonadAlt m where
(☐) :: m a -> m a -> m a
`This must saitsfy two laws`:
☐-associative: (p ☐ q) ☐ r = p ☐ (q ☐ r)
☐>>=dist: (p ☐ q) >>= f = (p >>= f) ☐ (q >>= f)

This is an interface that might be satisfied by a data type, but we are really interested with the interaction of choice
with failure.

I need to revise jujitsu arm locks

--NONDERTERMINISM
Choice and failure interacting together to give nondeterminism

you can bracket class conditions like so

class (MonadFail m, MonadAlt m) => MonadNonDet m where

this class adds no extra operations, it just depends on the other two

Then we have access to return, (>>=) ☐ and fail

we also impose an interaction between ☐ and fail, namely that fail is the unit of ☐, and so we form a monoid

right
fail-unit: p ☐ fail = p

left
fail-unit: fail ☐ p = p

//couldnt hear you
That's what I said
//???
You said something first
//aaaaaaaaah
//i asked what the shitstorm was about
lua
don't ask
//*asks*
Okay, so I said I'd do some lua for a game someone was making
Friend of a friend
Aaaand then I wake up to him freaking the fuck out because he has no idea what the code I wrote does
Because he has the ability with code of a goddamn goldfish
//did he not ask you to do something specific?
He did, then decided he needed to understand and modify it
He can't
//riiiiiiiiiiiiiiiight
//i'm starting to realise how often people have you help them with programming
Myah, I get sent some REALLY shitty code
Mostly lua
Eh, I get free karma for posting some of it to r/badcode
//hahahahaha

//how many hours did you sleep?
8ish, see I is good boy
//mama is proud
//i love how i'm both mum and the younger annoying sister
i tried to sleep for 9 hours but only slept for 7 bc there were too many planes/helicopters and it was unsettling me
Can't say I noticed any
//yeah my brain's like ' oh, mild inconvenience? guess i'm not sleeping for another half hour'
It's practice for when you'll end up being hunted by several governments
//one of the reasons i want to say on the legal side is that i'd literally fucking die of anxiety
Grey hat

-- IMPLEMENTATION

([] represents list as a type, not the empty list)
instance Monad [] where
--return :: a -> [a]
return x = [x]
-- (>>=) :: [a] -> (a -> [b]) -> [b]

The intuition for >>= is that xs >>= f we have :
xs = [x0, x1, x2, x3]
f is applied

[y00, y01] ++ [y10, y11, y12] ++ [] ++ [y30, y31, y32]

So, with this intuition, the definition of (>>=) is:
--(>>=) [a] -> (a-> [b]) -> [b]
xs >>= f = (concat . map f) xs

At this point we must prove the three monad laws. This is a good exercise - dewit

A list is also a MonadFail:

instance MonadFail [] where
	--fail :: [a]
	fail = []
we have to prove the fail-bind law:
fail >>= f = fail

fail >>= f
= {fail}
[] >>= f
= {>>=}
(concat . map f) []
={(.)}
concat (map f [])
={map}
concat []
={concat}
[]
={fail}
fail

instance MonadAlt [] where
(☐) :: [a] -> [a] -> [a]
xs ☐ ys = xs ++ ys -- or (☐) = (++)

Again we need to prove the MonadAlt laws

instance MonadNonDet [] where

there are no operations, but we do have to prove that fail ☐ q = q and fail ☐ p = p
and this is trivial

STAHP IT, GIT SOME HELP
:(
All that time, all you wanted to type was ":("?!
*sad nod*
Fucks sake Theano
what'd i do???!!
Voodoo
!!!
Burn the witch
why did you suddenly get so annoyed?
Good question, ask my childhood
*asks* *pokes with a stick*
WHat kind of stick?
birch?
Silver or paperbark?
silver
Good choice for poking stick, strong and whippy
i aint gonna whip anyone :P