Inhabitant = element
ie Inhabitants of Bool are True and False
Inhabitants of Unite: drunk, tipsy, smashed and fuck that ping pong table.
The difference between uni students and primary school kids is that the students are also drunk.

add (3,4) takes in Pair containing Ints 3 and 4
plus 3 4 takes in just Ints 3 and 4
plus 3 4 produces a function that adds three to an argument, then passes in the four to it to get the result.

curry add = plus
uncurry plus = add

> curry :: ((a,b) -> c) -> (a -> b -> c)
> curry f x y = f(x,y)

the reason that x:a and y:b can be put on the left of the "=" is that we can re-write the type of curry:

> curry :: ((a, b) -> c) -> a -> b -> c

Plot twist, f was the tanner

We could give a different definition using λ

> curry f = λ x -> (λ y -> f(x, y))

or

> curry f = λ x y -> f (x, y)

--Extensionality--

Two functions are equal if they agree on all outputs for all inputs

f = λx -> fx

Notepad doesn't speak greek. Well, mine does when I save in unicode.

Discord message pops up: "WHat the fuck is my family" - seems normal.
To be fair, Solomon's family ARE crazy.

The inverse of curry is uncurry - I'm leaving this line just to annoy you

> uncurry :: (a -> b -> c) -> ((a,b) -> c)
> uncurry g = λ(x, y) -> g x y

or

> uncurry :: (a -> b -> c) -> (a, b) -> c
> uncurry g (x, y) = g x y


--Prove that add and plus are roughly equivalent

plus x y
= {def. plus}
x + y
= {def. add}
add (x, y)

convert definition of plus

plus x y = x + y
<-> {extensionality}
plus x = λy -> x + y
<-> {extensionality}
plus = λx -> λy -> x + y
<-> {syntactic sugar}

plus = λ x y -> x + y