AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAGH ughm
Must recall or derive any function on the course
Memorise prelude functions
const (+1) :: b -> Int -> Int
const throws away the second argument
thinking. having trouble with that today.

---Monoids---
 -Associative
 -Has a neutral element

a + b + c = c + a + b
neutral element of + is 0

More generally, a monoid is an operation ⊕ with a neutral element ∅

Rules for a monoid
1. x ⊕ ∅ = x
2. ∅ ⊕ y = y
3. x ⊕ (y ⊕ z) = (x ⊕ y) ⊕ z

OR is monoid, neutral element false
AND neutral element true
function composition with identity
matrix multiplication with identity matrix
maximum of two numbers, neutral element -∞
minimum neutral element ∞
union, neutral element ∅
intersect, neutral all sets
matrix multiplication, neutral element identity matrix
function composition ".", neutral element identity function (echo)
[a] ++ [a], neutral element []

---Type classes---
Defines a family of types all related by their operations
Usually defined in terms of their operations and the laws that these operations must satisfy

For monoids:

class Monoid m where
	mappend :: m -> m -> m --⊕
	mempty :: m --∅

a valid instance of the Monoid class respects the monoid laws

instance Monoid Int where
	mappend = (+)
	mempty = 0


crush :: Monoid m => [m] -> m
crush = foldr mappend mempty
 