coursework not assessed, SAFE not used. assessment is 100% pen and paper exams. egh.
okay, I like this guy, but his addiction to pen and paper is infuriating

functional programming is programming with functions as values. this emphasis leads to programs that are usually concise, precise and reasonable.
short, do what they say, equational
origins are lambda calculus in 1930s by Alonzo Church
the curch-turing thesis showed that the λ-calculus is turing complete

λ-calculus made up of three things
- variables
- lambda abstraction
- application

Haskell is a modern language that implements λ-calc, conceived around 1990, released around 1998, based on Miranda

fib :: Int -> Int
fib 0 = 1
fib 1 = 1
fib n = fib(n - 1) + fib(n - 2)

pattern matching looks down the code until it finds the input (or a default, n) and executes the code behind it
haskell has no loops, only uses recursion

fib :: Int -> Int
is function name (fib) followed by type signiture (Int -> Int)
Types and Constructors start with Uppercase, vars start lowercase

--Types--

Int is fast, low precision - Integer is slower with infinite precision
Int is bound to 64 bit
Bool
Double
Char 'a'
String "aaaa"

<value> :: <Type>

value is contained in set Type

every value has a *principle type*, which means there exists a most general type,
such that all other types for that value are an instance of the principle type


--Functions--

Functions are mappings from values to values

maths
f(x) = x^2

haskell
f :: Integer -> Integer
f x = x * x

x is parameter
in f(5), 5 is argument

parameter is general, argument is specific actual value
type signitures are implicit in maths, explicit in haskell


--Evaluation--

sqaure :: Int -> Int
sqaure x = x * x

two :: Int -> Int
two n = 2

Evaluation is about substitution

square 5
= {def sqaure}
= 5 * 5
= {def *}
= 25

THIS FORMAT IS IMPORTANT, USE IN WORKSHEETS