Should that matrix have a four element diagonal Nic?
Theano has given up and is wearing her glasses today
FREEDOM! Fuck yeah!
Nic noticed the CS

type classes are general, instances give them implementation.

instance  Monoid Int where
	mappend = (+)
	mempty = 0
Problem:
Only valid for Int, cannot have another instance for Int, ie multiplication.

Solution: awful type hack. Great. Create a whole new type constructor to introduce a new type with same behavior as Int.

#NEWTYPES

newtype PInt = PInt Int

Similar to data, except it states that Int is almost isomorphic to PInt

To convert, use constructor PInt

toPint :: Int -> PInt
toPInt x = PInt x

Redundant, since it's just calling the constructor

To convert the other way

fromPInt :: PInt -> Int
fromPInt (PInt x) = x

Because the constructor can go backwards, holy shit Haskell.
Because PInt is a newtype of Int:

toPInt.fromPInt = id
fromPInt.toPInt = id

(id is identity or echo function)

The functions toPInt and fromPInt witness that PInt ≅ Int

An alternative notation for newtype automatically introduces the deconstructor

newtype PInt = PInt {unPInt :: Int}

Here:

toPInt = PInt and fromPInt = unPInt

To use this newtype for the PInt:

instance Monoid PInt where
mappend (PInt x) (PInt y) = PInt (x * y)
mempty = PInt 1

crush :: [PInt] -> PInt

We really wanted a function of type [Int] -> Int
We do so as this:
[Int]
-map PInt
[PInt]
-crush
PInt
-unPInt
Int

This is what we want, and it is code
unPInt.crush.Map PInt

This was a horrible mess, never use it in this case

-------------------------------------------------

There are lots of type classes (no shit Nic)
Some from prelude:

class Eq a where
	(==) :: a -> a -> Bool

for instance, equality on bools:
instance Eq Bool where
	--(==) :: Bool -> Bool -> Bool
	True == True = True
	False == False = True
	_ == _ = False

Haskell is able to derive the Eq type class by itself:

data Bool = True | False
	deriving Eq

Another type class is Num, which allows us to write numbers:

class Num a where
	(+) :: a -> a -> a
	(-) :: a -> a -> a
	(*) :: a -> a -> a
	negate :: a -> a
	abs :: a -> a
	signum a -> a
	fromInteger :: Int -> a

This is implemented for Int, Integer, Float, Double.